Guide to the Robert T. Clausen papers, [ca. 1930-1980]
Clausen, Robert T. papers, [ca. 1930-1980]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert T. Clausen papers, [ca. 1930-1980]
34-1-2585
Robert T.(Theodore), Clausen 1911-
32 cubic ft.
Correspondence, meeting minutes, journals, field notebooks, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Journals and field notes relating to Mexican trips, 1970s; correspondence relating to professional matters, including the Cornell Plantations; journals, 1950s-1970s; and miscellaneous field notes, herbarium records, and teaching records.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Biology, Cornell University.
Cornell University B.A. 1933; M.A. 1934; Ph.D. 1937.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Journals and field notes relating to Mexican trips, 1970s; correspondence relating to professional matters, including the Cornell Plantations; journals, 1950s-1970s; and miscellaneous field notes, herbarium records, and teaching records.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Clausen, Robert T.1911-; Cornell Plantations.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Biology--Study and teaching.; Herbaria--New York (State)--Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Notebooks from Research Trips/Journals
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Cornell Plantations - Correspondence and Meeting Minutes
Series IV. Course Materials
Series V. Data on Finger Lakes Region Plants
Series VI. Reprints
Series VII. Field Research
Series VIII. Wiegand Herbarium
Series IX. Records
Series X. Sedum
Series XI. Plant Data
Series XII. Photos
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Notebooks from Research Trips/Journals
  - Research trips to Mexico and the Western U.S., 1976-1981 (Box 1)
    Forming the basis of Clausen's study on Sedum of the Mexican Plateau. In addition to discussing the specimens, geololgy, and vegetation of the areas canvasssed, Clausen recorded details on the logistics of the trips
  - Field records from his research trips, 1940-1980 (Box 6)
    Field records from his research trips, including Glaciated Allegheny Plateau, 1975-80; Sedimentary Appalachian Mts., 1966; Central Rocky Mts., 1966, Red Mtn., Mammoth, Devils River, 1970; Cascade Mts.; Piedmont Plateau: San Bernadino Mts., 1940, 1963, 1968. Additionally, Clausen kept records of his interests in Ithaca and Cornell, such as the Herbarium; Greenhouse in Slaterville Springs; Botany Courses, 1964-5; Taxonomy Courses, 1966; and his personal possesions at Cornell, 1971.
  - Journals, excluding major research trips, 1953-1970 (Box 4)
  - Journals - Clausen recorded items from both his personal and professional life., 1960-1980 (Box 5)
  - Journals, trip notebooks, field notes, agenda, experiment records, 1949-1981 (Box 22)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - A-Abb, 1955-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Abd-And, 1956-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - And-Auc, 1958-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bac-Bar, 1958-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bar-Bla, 1954-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bla-But, 1953-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cac-Cas, 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cat-Coo, 1954-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Coo-Cor, 1963-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cor-Cut, 1960-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - D, 1949-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - E, 1958-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - F, 1954-1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - G, 1953-1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - H, 1957-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - I, 1950-1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - J, 1948-1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Kan-Ken, 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ken-Kur, 1956-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - L, 1956-1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Maa-Mil, 1958-1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Mil-Mey, 1954-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - McC-McV, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - N, 1954-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - O, 1958-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - P, 1940-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Q, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - R, 1954-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sab-She, 1955-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Shi-Spi, 1954-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Spi-Swe, 1956-1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - T, 1952-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - U, 1954-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - V, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - W, 1964-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Y, 1948-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Z, 1948-1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Annual Report on the Sale on the Book "Sedum of the Trans-Mexican Volcanic Belt", 1950s to 1970s (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence on the book of "Sedum of the Trans-Mexican Volcanic Belt", 1950s to 1960s (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Abbey Garden Press, 1940s to 1950s (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence on Aerial Photographs, 1960s to 1980s (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Brochures on NY Botanical Garden, 1960s to 1970s (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence on Obtaining Specimen, 1950s to 1970s (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence on Guggenheim Fund Grant, 1954 - 1955 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Series III. Cornell Plantations - Correspondence and Meeting Minutes
  - Cornell Plantation Committee Meeting Minutes, 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Plantation Committee Meeting Minutes, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, reports on Cornell Natural Area 1, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, reports on Cornell Natural Area 2, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, reports on Cornell Natural Area 3, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series IV. Course Materials
  - Taxonomy - Literature Exercises (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Bio Sciences 346, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Taxonomy & Ecology of Vascular Plants - Botany 118, 1940's-60 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Taxonomy & Ecology of Vascular Plants - Botany 118, 1940's-50 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - South Hill sampling unit no. 3270 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Botany A117 Ringwood (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Central Glaciated Allegheny Plateau (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Trees and Shrubs - Cornell Campus and Vicinity (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Flower Structure and Arrangement (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Biological Sciences 346 - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Biological Sciences 341 - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Project 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Biological Sciences 371 - Autumnal Coloration of Foliage (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Biological Sciences 346 - Guides to the Literature on Vascular Plants (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Botany 117 - Fruits of Angiosperms (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Botany 117 - Psilotinae, Articulatae (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Report on Family (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Midterm, Oct. 17, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Biological Sciences 371 - Random Sample #3 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Biological Sciences 371 - Topics for Lectures and Readings, Autumn, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Taxonomy - Topics and References, Lectures 21-28, Autumn, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Biological Sciences 371, Jan.-Sept. 1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Reports - Salix Project, Sept. 1975 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Examinations, 1956-77 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Taxonomy - Monocot Examination, March 9, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Taxonomy Examinations, 1948-76 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Course Material (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Trees and Shrubs (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Taxonomy and Botany - Lecture Notes, 1942-63 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Master Copy of Outlines, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - History of Botany (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Botany - Summer Session, Summer 1949-60 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Botany 117 - Registration Sheets, 1953-1974 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Taxonomy - Grading (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Biology 464 - Old Notes (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Taxonomy and Ecology, Spring 1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Phytogeography of the Cayuga Lake Basin (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Phytogeography of the Ithaca Region (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Botany 418, Spring 1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Evolution and Ecology, Spring 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Evolution and Ecology of Vascular Plants, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Evolution and Ecology of Vascular Plants, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Project on Drainage of Six Mile Creek, Spring 1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Seminar in Taxonomy, Spring 1955 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Seminar in Taxonomy, 1947-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bio. Sci. 663 - Seminar, Fall 1972, 1974-5 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Taxonomy - Summary (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Botany 117 - Old Records and Notes (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Taxonomy - General Notes (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Schedule, Spring 1977 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Taxonomy Courses - assistants (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants - Outlines (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Bio. Sci. 371, Spring 1977 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Lisa Standley - Master's Thesis (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Courses - Supplies, February 1970 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Ophioglossaceae (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Standley - Thesis Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Nomenclature - Rules (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Paleobotany (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Taxonomy - Sources of Information (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Variation and Classification (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Taxonomy Course (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Order Najadales (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Botany 118 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Taxonomy - Advanced Course (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Botany 118 - examinations (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Vascular Plants - Evolution and Ecology Outline (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Bio. Sci. 466 - Outline, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Kinds of Species (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Polymorphic Species - Lecture 1 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Polymorphic Species - Lecture 2 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Isolating Mechanisms and Incompatibility (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Evolution and Chromosomal Changes (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Polyploidy, Autoploidy, Polygonatum (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Polyploidy 2 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - The Species in Asexual Groups (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Hybridization in Nature - pt. 1 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Hybridization in Nature - pt. 2 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Centers of Origin - 1 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Sampling (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Reproduction and Local Population (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Variation with Local Population (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Natural Population (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Origin, Growth and Disapearance of Local Population (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Effect of Man on Natural Population (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Environmental Diversity and the Origin of Species (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Competition - Lecture 21 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Summary, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Taxonomy, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Bio. Sci. 346 - 1 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Bio. Sci. 346 - 2 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Central America (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Trop. N.A. - General (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Africa (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - South America (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Europe (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Iceland (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Asia (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Geographic Isolation and Evolution (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pacific Ocean (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Hawaiian Islands (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Aristochiages, Juglandales, Fagales, Muricales (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Ericales (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Filicinae and Lower Classes (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Bio S 371, Fall, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Botany 117 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Bio. Sci. 371, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Surveys (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Botany 117 - Lecture Notes (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Taxonomy of Vascualr Plants A (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants B (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Stems and Leaves (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Sampling 1 and 2, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Filicinae and lower classes - Part 1 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Class Filicinae (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Family Polypodiaceae (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Indusia, Sori, and Sporangia (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - References on Pteridophytes (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Pteridophytes (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Gymnosperms (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Classification of Vascular Plants (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Sapindales (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Acer Laboratory (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Malvales and Geraniales (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Geographical Distribution of Vascular Plants (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Centrospermae and Primidales (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Sapotaceae (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Aerial Photographs (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Aristolochiales (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Project (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Directions for Fieldwork (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Vascular Plants, Spring, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Mainland Species, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Monomorphic Species (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Endemism (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Endemic Regions (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Myrtales, Umbrellales, Rubiales (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Laboratory Specimens (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Lists of Species for Recognition (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Leaves Laboratory (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Flowers (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Fruits (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Variation (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Woody Plants in Winter (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Ranales (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Papaveraceae (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Bio. Sci. 341: Evolutionary Relationships - bog/flora, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Bio. Sci. 341: Evolutionary Relationships - Plants of Acid, Poorly Drained Soil, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants Cyperales - Pasceae, 1940s to 1960s (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants Gymnosperms, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Taxonomy of Vascular Plants Liliales, Orchidales, Xyriadales, 1940s to 1960s (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Taxonomy - lecture 15 Magnoliales, 1950s to 1970s (Box 20, Folder 30)
- Series V. Data on Finger Lakes Region Plants
  - New York - Dioscoreaceal (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Cayuga Quad. - Hydrocharitacere (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Glac. Allegh. Plat. - Iridaceae (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Cayuga Lake Region - Juncaceal (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Juncaginaceae (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Glac. Allegh. Plat. - Lemnaceal (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Glac. Allegheny Plateau - Liliaceal (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Cayug Quad. - Najadaceae (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Glac. Alleg. Plat. - Orchidaceae (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Glac. Alleg. Plat. - Poaceae (Gramineae) (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Cayuga Quad. - Pontederiaceae (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Finger Lakes Region - Potamogetonaceae (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Ithaca region, NY - Sparganiaceae (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Appalachian Highlands - Typhaceae (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Vascular Plants of the Glaciated Allegheny Plateau (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Asclepiadaceae (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Berberidaceae (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Betulaceae (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Boriginaceae (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Brassicaceae (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Amaranthaceae (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Umbelliferae (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Araliaceae (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Viburnum (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Cucurbitaceae (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Hamamelidaceae (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ericaceae - Vaccinium (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Euphorbiaceal (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Leguminosal (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Fagaceae (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Fumariceae (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Gentianaceae (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Geraniaceae (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Illecebraceae (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Halorhagaceae (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Hydrophyllaceae (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Hypericaceal (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Loganiaceae (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Lythraceae (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Magnoliaceae (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Melastomaceae (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Moraceae (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Juglandaceae (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Myricateae (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Malvaceae (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Loranthaceal (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Lobeliaceae (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Linaceae (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Limnanthaceae (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Lentibulariaceae (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Lauraceae (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Lamiaceae (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Ericaceae - Vaccinium (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Ericaceae (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Oxalidaceae (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Plants - P (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Rosaceae (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Crataegus (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Rosaceae - Rubus (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Rubiaceae (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Rutaceae (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Salicaceae (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Salicaceae - Salix (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Salix (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Salix - Survey (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Plants - S (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Scrophulariaceae (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Solanaceae (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Plants - T (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Plants - U (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - Plants - V (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Viola (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Vitaceae (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Monocotyledoneae (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Alismataceae (Box 12, Folder 60)
  - Araceae (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - Commelinaceae (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - Cyperaceae (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - Carex (Box 12, Folder 64)
- Series VI. Reprints- In box 7
- Series VII. Field Research
  - Pacific Border Province - Southern (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Shield - Grenville Province (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Chopaka Mt. Sampling Area no. 19, July 1965 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Cascade Mountains - Okanogan, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Cascade Mts. - Northern Skagit Range, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cascade Mts. - Three Sisters, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Pacific Border Province - Gabilan Mts., 1963 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Pacific Border Province - Mayacmas (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Pacific Border Province - Perris Upland, 1962-3 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pacific Border Province - Sacramento Valley (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Pacific Border Province - Santa Monica Mts. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Pacific Border Province - Southern Coast Range, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Pacific Border Province - Southern Willamette Valley, 1962-3 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Pacific Border Province - Yolla Bolly Mts., 1963 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Cascade Mts. - Three Sisters Data, July 1965 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Old Deer Butte Trail Unit, July 1965 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Swamp Creek Unit, Summer 1965 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Mud Lake Unit - Aerial Photos, 1965-6 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Cascade Mts. - O'Leary Mt., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Wenachee Mts., Washington, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Geographic Notes (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Santanoni Quad. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - North America - Green Mts. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - North Eastern Temperate N.A. - General (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Vermont (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Geology and Geography (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - World (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - North America (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - N.A. - Saskatchewan Plateau (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - N.A. - Northern Rocky Mountains (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - N.A. - New England Seaboard Lowland (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - N.A. - New England Upland (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Middle Rocky Mountains (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - N.A. - Lawrentian Upland (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - N.A. - Labrador Penninsula (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - North America - Greenland (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - North America - Geology (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Records - map of North America (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Aleutian Islands (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Arctic N.A. - General (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - N.A. - Eastern (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - N.A. Eastern - Monocotyledoneae (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - S.E. Temp. N.A. - General (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Temp. S.E. N.A. - 2 Carolinas and Georgia (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - North America - Western (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - North America - Dicotyledoneae (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Vascular Plands of the Northern Appalachian Quad. (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Appalachian Ridge and Valley, May 18 - June 14, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - N.A. - Appalachian Highlands (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Addresses and Brochure (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - N.A. - Great Plains, Black Hills (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Blue Ridge (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Blue Ridge - Brasstown Bald (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Canadian Shield (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - N.A. Cascade Mts. (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - N.A. - Middle Cascade Mts. (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - N.A. Central Lowland (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - N.A. - Central Lowland, Great Lakes Plain (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Central Rocky Mountains (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Central Rocky Mts. - Grand Tetons (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Central Rocky Mts. - Teton Range (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - N.A. - Coastal Plain (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - N.A. Coastal Plain (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - N.A. - Embayed Coastal Plain (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - N.A. - Colorado Plateau (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Appalachian Plateau - Cumberland Plateau (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - N.A. Great Plains (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Crawford Quad, Neb. (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Black Butte Quad. (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Taxonomy Lecture 51 - Black Butte Quad (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Klamath Mt. - Rogue River National Forest (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - N.A. - Missouri Plateau, Unglaciated (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - New England (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - N.A. New England - Acadian region (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - N.W. Temp. N.A. - General (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - N.A. - Ouachita Mts. (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - N.A. - Pacific Mt. System (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Sedum - Pacific Mt. System (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - N.A. - Piedmont Plateau (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - N.A. Ridge and Valley Province (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Sierra Nevada, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Sierra Nevada - South Yosemite (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Southern Rocky Mts. (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Sedum - Southern Rocky Mountains (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - S.W. Temp. N.A. - General (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - N.A. White Mountains (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - N.A. - Wyoming Basin (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Canada (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Canada - Ontario (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Alaska (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - California (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - United States (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - North Carolina (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - California - Maps (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Florida (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Georgia (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Idaho, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Indiana (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Michigan (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Nebraska (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - North Carolina - Maps (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Ohio (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Oregon (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - South Carolina (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Virginia (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Washington (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - West Virginia - Maps (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Mexico - Oaxaca (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Central America - Panama (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Quad. Locations and References (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - New York (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Mexico - Maps (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Other States (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Western North America Expedition (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Taos Quad (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Series VIII. Wiegand Herbarium
  - Botanical Books and Serials for Cornell Library, 1947&1961 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Curator Papers (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Cases (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Biology - Linnaeus (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Chicago (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Herbaria (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Herbarium of R.T. Clausen, 1939-70 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Horticulture (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hybrids (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Permits (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Plant Species - Alphabetically (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Slides - Numbers (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Maps (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - World Aeronautical Charts (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Mathematics (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Marvin Mead (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Meteorology (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Microscope (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Miscellanies - Books (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Distribution of a Species (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Washington (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Wiegand Herbarium (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Wilcoxon Rank Sum Test (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Wiegand, K.M. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Memos and Notes on Herbarium - 60s to early 80s, 1960s to 1980s (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Daily Botanical Records of Kathy Krathwohl, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Records - Wiegand Herbarium, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 34)